         BRA      MVPS'
DOQUO1 CMP.B      DO,D1             make sure we're ending proper quote
         BNE      TOUPB1            if not, ignore it
         CLR.B    Dl                else clear quote flag
         BRA      TOUPBI

•
•        Convert the character in DO to upper case
•
TOUPPER CMP.B     ea',D0            is it < 'a'?
         BCS      TOUPRET
         CMP.B    l'z',D0           or > 'z'?
         SKI      TOUPRET
         SUB.B    032,D0            if not, make it upper case
TOUPRET RTS

•
• 'CHKIO' checks the input. If there's no input, it will return
• to the caller with the 2 flag set. If there is input, the 2
• flag is cleared and the input byte is in DO. However, if a
• control-C is read, 'CHKIO' will warm-start BASIC and will not
• return to the caller.
•
CHKIO    BSR.L    COIN              get input if possible
         BEQ      CHKRET            if Zero, no input
         CMP.B    OCTRLC,DO         is it control-C?
         BNE      CHKRET            if not
         BRA.L    MSTART            if so, do a warm start
CHKRET RTS

•
• Display a CR-LF sequence
•
CRLF     LEA      CLMSG,A6

•
• Display a zero-ended string pointed to by register A6
•
PRMESG MOVE.B     (,116)+,D0        get the char.
         SEC      PRMRET            if it's zero, we're done
         BSR      GOOUT             else display it
         BRA      PRMESG
PRMRET RTS



• The following routines are the only ones that need •
• to be changed for a different I/O environment.     •



•
• Output character to the console (Port 1) from register DO
•        (Preserves all registers.)
•
OUTC     BTST     11,610040         is port 1 ready for a character?
         BEID     OUTC              if not, wait for it
         MOVE.B D0,$10042           out it gots.
         RTS

•
•        Input a character from the console into register DO (or
•        return Zero status if there's no character available).

