• to the caller. If underline, outputs a CR without a LF. If single
• or double quote, prints the quoted string and demands a matching
• end quote. After the printing, the next 2 bytes of the caller are
• skipped over (usually a short branch instruction).
•
• 'PRTNUM' prints the 32 bit number in DI, leading blanks are added if
• needed to pad the number of spaces to the number in D4.
• However, if the number of digits is larger than the no. in
• D4, all digits are printed anyway. Negative sign is also
• printed and counted in, positive sign is not.
•
• 'PRTLN' prints the saved text line pointed to by Al
• with line no. and all.
•
PRTSTG MOVE.B D0,D1            save the stop character
PSI     MOVE.B (A1)+,D0        get a text character
        CMP.B  DO,D1           same as stop character?
        BEQ    PRTRET          if so, return
        BSR    GOOUT           display the char.
        CMP.B  NCR,D0          is it a C.R.?
        BNE    PSI             no, go back for more
        MOVE.B MLF,D0          yes, add a L.F.
        BSR    GOOUT
PRTRET RTS                     then return

QTSTG   BSR.L  TSTC            ••• OTSTG •••
        DC.B   "',01T3-* 
        MOVE.8 O'"',D0         it is a"
QT1     MOVE.L AO,A1 
        BSR    PRTSTG          print until another
        MOVE.L A1,AO 
        MOVE.L (SP)+,A1        pop return address 
        CMP.B  OLF,D0          was last one a CR? 
        BEG    RUNNXL          if so, run next line
QT2     ADDQ.L #2,A1           skip 2 bytes on return 
        JMP    (Al)            return
QT3     BSR.L  TSTC            is it a single quote?
        DC.B   "",QT4-*
        MOVE.B 11"",00         if 30, do same as above
        BRA    QT1
QT4     BSR.L  TSTC            is it an underline?
        DC.B 
        MOVE.B OCR,D0          if so, output a CR without LF 
        BSR.L  GOOUT 
        MOVE.L (SP)+,A1        pop return address
        BRA    QT2
QT5     RTS                    none of the above

PRTNUM MOVE.L  D1,D3           save the number for later
        MOVE   D4,-(SP)        save the width value
        MOVE.B #$FF,-(Sp)      flag for end of digit string 
        TST.L  DI              is it negative?
        BPL    PN1             if not
        NEG.L  DI              else make it positive 
        SUBQ   01,04           one less for width count
PN1     DIVU   #10, D1         get the next digit 
        BVS    PNOV            overflow flag set?
        MOVE.L D1, D0          if not, save remainder 
        AND.L  liSFEFF,D1      strip the remainder 
        BRA    TOASCII         skip the overflow stuff
PNOV    MOVE   D1,D0           prepare for long word division

