RUNNXL  TST.L   CURRNT                 ;executing a program?
        BEQ     WSTART                 ;if not, we've finished a direct stat.
        CLR.L   D1                     ;else find the next line number
        MOVE.L  A0,A1
        BSR     FNDLNP
        BCS     WSTART                 ;if we've fallen off the end, stop

RUNTSL  MOVE.L  Al,CURRNT                       ;set CURRNT to point to the line no. 
        MOVE.L  A1,A0                  ;set the text pointer to
        ADDQ.L  #2,A0                  ;the start of the line text

RUNSML  BSR     CHKIO                  ;see if a control-C was pressed 
        LEA     TAB2,A1                ;find command in TAB2
        LEA     TAB2_1,A2
        BRA     EXEC                   ;and execute it

GOTO    BSR     EXPR                   ;evaluate the following expression
        BSR     ENDCHK                 ;must find end of line
        MOVE.L  D0,D1
        BSR     FNDLN                  ;find the target line
        BNE     QHOW                   ;no such line no.
        BRA     RUNTSL                 ;go do it

*
********************************************************************
*
* *** LIST 0* PRINT ***
*
* LIST has two forms:
* 'LIST<CR>' lists all saved lines
* 'LIST *<CR>I starts listing at the line II
* Control-S pauses the listing, control-C stops it.
*
* PRINT command is 'PRINT              or 'PRINT ....<CR>'
* where '....' is a list of expressions, formats, back-arrows,
* and strings. These Items a separated by commas.
*
* A format is a pound sign followed by a number. It controls
* the number of spaces the value of an expression is going to
* be printed in. It stays effective for the rest of the print
* command unless changed by another format. If no format is
* specified, 11 positions will be used.
*
* A string is quoted in a pair of single- or double-quotes.
*
* An underline (back-arrow) means generate a <CR> without a <LF>
*
* A <CR LF> is generated after the entire list has been printed
* or if the list is empty. If the list ends with a semicolon,
* however, no <CR LF> is generated.
*

LIST    BSR     TSTNUM                 see if there's a line no.
        BSR     ENDCHK                 if not, we get a zero
        BSR     FNDLN                  find this or next line
LS1     BCS     WSTART                 warm start if we passed the end
        BSR     PRTLN                  print the line
        BSR     CHKIO                  check for listing halt request
        BEQ     LS3
        CMP.B   #CTRLS,D0              pause the listing?

