* 'RETURN<CR>' undoes everything that 'GOSUB' did, and thus
* returns the execution to the command after the most recent
* 'GOSUB'. If 'STKGOS' is zero, it indicates that we never had
* a 'GOSUB' and is thus an error.
*
GOSUB	BSR.L	PUSHA           ;save the current 'FOR' parameters  
        BSR.L	EXPR            ;get line number
        MOVE.L	A0,-(SP)        ;save text pointer
        MOVE.L  DO,D1           
        BSR.L	FNDLN           ;find the target line
        BNE.L	AHOW            ;if not there, say "How?"
        MOVE.L  CURRNT,-(SP)    ;found it, save old 'CURRNT'... 
        MOVE.L	STKGOS,-(SP)    ;and 'STKGOS'
        CLR.L	LOPVAR          ;load new values
        MOVE.L  SP,STKGOS       
        BRA	    RUNTSL          

RETURN  BSR.L   ENDCHK          ;there should be just a <CR>
        MOVE.L  STKGOS,D1       ;get old stack pointer
        BEQ.L	QWHAT           ;if zero, it doesn't exist
        MOVE.L  D1,SP           ;else restore it
        MOVE.L  (SP)+,STKGOS    ;and the old 'STKGOS'
        MOVE.L  (SP)+,CURRNT    ;and the old 'CURRNT'
        MOVE.L  (SP)+,A0        ;and the old text pointer
        BSR.L   POPA            ;and the old 'FOR' parameters
        BRA	    FINISH          ;and we are back home
  
*
********************************************************************
*
* *** FOR *** & NEXT ***
* 'FOR' has two forms:
* 'FOR var-expl TO exp2 STEP expl' and 'FOR var-expl TO exp2'
* The second form means the same thing as the first form with a
* STEP of positive 1. The interpreter will find the variable 'var'
* and set its value to the current value of 'expl'. It also
* evaluates 'exp2' and 'expl' and saves all these together with
* the text pointer, etc. in the 'FOR' save area, which consisits of
* 'LOPVAR', 'LOPINC', 'LOPLMT', 'LOPLN', and 'LOPPT'. If there is
* already something in the save area (indicated by a non-zero
* ILOPVAR'1, then the old save area is saved on the stack before
* the new values are stored. The interpreter will then dig in the
* stack and find out if this same variable was used in another
* currently active 'FOR' loop. If that is the case, then the old
* 'FOR' loop is deactivated. (i.e. purged from the stack)
*
* 'NEXT var' serves as the logical (not necessarily physical) end
* of the 'FOR' loop. The control variable 'var' is checked with
* the 'LOPVAR'. If they are not the same, the interpreter digs in
* the stack to find the right one and purges all those that didn't
* match. Either way, it then adds the 'STEP' to that variable and
* checks the result with against the limit value. If it is within
* the limit, control loops back to the command following the
* 'FOR'. If it's outside the limit, the save area is purged and
* execution continues.
*
FOR	    BSR.L   PUSHA           ;save the old 'FOR' save area
        BSR.L   SETVAL          ;set the control variable
        MOVE.L  A6,LOPVAR       ;save its address
        LEA	    TAB5,A1         ;use 'EXEC' to test for 'TO'

