• 'IF' is followed by an expression, as a condition and one or
• more commands (including other 'IF's) separated by colons.
• Note that the word 'THEN' is not used. The interpreter evaluates
• the expression. If it is non-zero, execution continues. If it
• is zero, the commands that follow are ignored and execution
• continues on the next line.
•
• 'INPUT' is like the 'PRINT' command, and is followed by a list
• of items. If the item is a string in single or double quotes,
• or is an underline (back arrow), it has the same effect as in
• 'PRINT'. If an item is a variable, this variable name is
• printed out followed by a colon, then the interpreter waits for
• an expression to be typed in. The variable is then set to the
• value of this expression. If the variable is proceeded by a
• string (again in single or double quotes), the string will be
• displayed followed by a colon. The interpreter the waits for an
• expression to be entered and sets the variable equal to the
• expression's value. If the input expression is invalid, the
• interpreter will print "What?", "How?", or "Sorry" and reprint
• the prompt and redo the input. The execution will not terminate
• unless you press control-C. This is handled in 'INPERR'.

• 'LET' is followed by a list of items separated by commas.
• Each item consists of a variable, an equals sign, and an
• expression. The interpreter evaluates the expression and sets
• the variable to that value. The interpreter will also handle
• 'LET' commands without the word 'LET'. This is done by 'DEFLT'.

REM    BRA     IF2           skip the rest of the line

IF     BSR.L   EXPR          evaluate the expression 
IF1    TST.L   DO            is it zero?
       BNE     RUNSML        if not, continue
IF2    MOVE.L AO,A1
       CLR.L   01
       BSR.L   FNDSKP        if so, skip the rest of the line 
       BCC     RUNTSL        and run the next line
       BRA.L   WSTART        if no next line, do a warm start

INPERR MOVE.L STKINP,SP      restore the old stack pointer 
       MOVE.L  (SP)+,CURRNT  and old 'CURRNT'
       ADDO.L t4,SP
       MOVE.L  (SP)+,A0      and old text pointer

INPUT  MOVE.L  AO, - (SP)    save in case of error 
       BSR.L   QTSTG         is next item a string? 
       BRA.S   IP2           nope
       BSR.L   TSTV          yes, but is it followed by a variable? 
       BCS     IP4           if not, branch
       MOVE.L  DO,A2         put away the variable's address
       BRA     IP3           if so, input to variable 
IP2    MOVE.L  AO, - (SP)    save for 'PRTSTG'
       BSR.L   TSTV          must be a variable now 
       BCS.L   ()WHAT        "What?" it isn't?
       MOVE.L  DO,A2         put away the variable's address
       MOVE.B  (AO),D2       get ready for 'PRTSTG'
       CLR.B   DO
       MOVE.B  DO,(A0) 
       MOVE.L  (SP)+,A1 
       BSR.L   PRTSTG        print string as prompt 
       MOVE.B  D2, (A0)      restore text

