QWHAT   MOVE.L   AO,-(SP)
AWHAT   LEA      WHTMSG,A6
ERROR   BSR.L    PRMESG           display the error message
        MOVE.L   (SP)•,A0         restore the text pointer
        MOVE.!.  CURRNT,DO        get the current line number
        BEQ      WSTART           if zero, do a warm start
        CMP.L    N-1,D0           is the line no. pointer • -1?
        BEQ      INPERR           if so, redo Input
        MOVE.B   I/Oh-(SP)        save the char. pointed to
        CLR.B    (AO)             put a zero where the error is
        MOVE.L   CURRNT,A1        point to start of current line
        BSR.L    PRTLN            display the line in error up to the 0
        MOVE.B   (SP)+, (AO)      restore the character
        MOVE.B   f'?',D0          display a "?"
        BSR      GOOUT
        CLR      DO
        SUB().!, 01,A1            point back to the error char.
        BSR.L    PRTSTG           display the rest of the line
        BRA      WSTART           and do a warm start
()SORRY MOVE.L   A0,-(SP)
ASORRY LEA       SRYMSG,A6
        BRA      ERROR
OHOW    MOVE.L   A0,-(SP)         Error: "How?"
AHOW    LEA      HOWMSG,A6
•       BRA      ERROR

•
• on GETLN ••• FNDLN (4 friends) •••
•
• 'GETLN' reads in input line into 'BUFFER'. It first prompts with
• the character in DO (given by the caller), then it fills the
• buffer and echos. It ignores LF's but still echos
• them back. Control-H is used to delete the last character
• entered (if there is one), and control-K is used to delete the
• whole line and start over again. CR signals the end of a line,
• and causes 'GETLN' to return.

• 'FNDLN' finds a line with a given line no. lin Dl) in the
• text save area. Al is used as the text pointer. If the line
• is found, Al will point to the beginning of that line
• (i.e. the high byte of the line no.), and flags are NC G Z.
• If that line is not there and a line with a higher line no.
• is found, Al points there and flags are NC d NZ. If we reached
• the end of the text save area and cannot find the line, flags
• are C 6 NZ.
• 'FNDLN' will initialize Al to the beginning of the text save
• area to start the search. Some other entries of this routine
• will not initialize Al and do the search.
• 'FNDLNP' will start with Al and search for the line no.
• 'FNDNXT' will bump Al by 2, find a CR and then start search.
• 'FNDSKP' uses Al to find a CR, and then starts the search.

GETLN   BSR      GOOUT            display the prompt
        MOVE.B 0",D0              and a space
        BSR      GOOUT
        LEA      BUFFER,AC        AO is the buffer pointer
GLI     HSR.I.   CHKIO            check keyboard
        BEQ      GL1              wait for a char. to come in
        CNP.B    fCTRLH,D0        delete last character?

