         AND.B     #$7F,D1                       ;ignore the table's high bit
         OMP.B     DO,D1                         ;is there a match?
         BEQ       EXMAT
         ADDQ.L    #2,A2                         ;if not, try the next entry
         MOVE.L A3,A0                            ;reset the program pointer
         CLR.B     D2                            ;sorry, no match
EXI      TST.B     (Al)+                         ;get to the end of the entry
         BPL       EX1
         BRA       EXLP                          ;back for more matching
EXMAT    MOVEQ     #-1,D2                        ;we've got a match so far
         TST.B     (Al)+                         ;end of table entry?
         BPL       EXLP                          ;if not, go back for more
ExGo     LEA       0,A3                          ;execute the appropriate routine
         MOW       (A2),A3
         JMP       (A3)
*
********************************************************************
* What follows is the code to execute direct and statement
* commands. Control is transferred to these points via the command
* table lookup code of 'DIRECT' and 'EXEC' in the last section.
* After the COMMand is executed, control is transferred to other
* sections as follows:
*
* For 'L:ST', 'NEW', and 'STOP': go back to the warm start point.
* For 'RUN': go execute the first stored line if any; else go
* back to the warm start point.
* For 'GOTO' and 'GOSUB': go execute the target line.
* For 'RETURN' and 'NEXT'; go back to saved return line.
* For all others: if 'CURRNT' is 0, go to warm start; else go
* execute next command. (This is done in 'FINISH'.)
*
********************************************************************
*
* "4 NEW *** STOP *** RUN       friends) "" GOTO ***
*
* 'NEW<CR,' sets TXTUNF to point to TXTBGN
*
* ISTOP<CR>s goes back to WSTART
*
* 'RUN<CR>' finds the first stored line, stores its address
* in CURRNT, and starts executing it. Note that only those
* commands in TAB? are legal for a stored program.
*
* There are 3 more entries in 'RUN':
* 'RUt'NXL' finds next line, stores it's address and executes it.
* 'RUNTS1... stores the address of this line and executes it.
* 'RUNSML' continues the execution on same line.
*
* 'GOTO expr<CR>' evaluates the expression, finds the target
* line, and lumps to 'RUNTSL' to do it.
*
NEW      BSR      ENDCHK
         MOVE.L   TXTBGN,TXTUNF          ;set the end pointer

STOP     BSR      ENDCHK
         BRA      WSTART

RUN      BSR.     ENDCHK
         MOVE.L   TXTBGN,AC              ;set pointer to beginning
         MOVE.L   A0,CURRNT

