RUNNXL TST.L           CURRNT                 executing a program?
           BEQ.L       WSTART                 if not, we've finished a direct stat.
           CLR.L       DI                     else find the next line number
           MOVE.L      AO,A1
           BSR.L       FNDLNP
           BCS         WSTART                 if we've fallen off the end, stop

RUNTSL MOVE.L Al,CURRNT                       set CURRNT to point to the line no. 
           MOVE.L      AI,A0                  set the text pointer to
           ADDQ.L      12,A0                  the start of the line text

RUNSML BSR.L           CHKIO                  see if a control-C was pressed 
           LEA         TAB2,A1                find command in TAB2
           LEA         TAB2.1,A2
           BRA         EXEC                   and execute it

GOTO       BSR.L       EXPR                   evaluate the following expression
           BSR.L       ENDCHK                 must find end of line
           MOVE.L      DO,D1
           BSR.L       FNDLN                  find the target line
           BNE.L       QHOW                   no such line no.
           BRA         RUNTSL                 go do it

•


• ••• LIST 0* PRINT •••
•
• LIST has two forms:
• 'LIST<CR>' lists all saved lines
• 'LIST •<CR>I starts listing at the line II
• Control-S pauses the listing, control-C stops it.

• PRINT command is 'PRINT              or 'PRINT ....<CR>'
• where '....' is a list of expressions, formats, back-arrows,
• and strings. These Items a separated by commas.

• A format is a pound sign followed by a number. It controls
• the number of spaces the value of an expression is going to
• be printed in. It stays effective for the rest of the print
• command unless changed by another format. If no format is
• specified, 11 positions will be used.

• A string is quoted in a pair of single- or double-quotes.

• An underline (back-arrow) means generate a <CR> without a <LF>

• A <CR LF> is generated after the entire list has been printed
• or if the list is empty. If the list ends with a semicolon,
• however, no <CR LF> is generated.


LIST       BSR.L       TSTNUM                 see if there's a line no.
           BSR.L       ENDCHK                 if not, we get a zero
           BSR.L       FNDLN                  find this or next line
LS1        BCS         WSTART                 warm start if we passed the end
           BSR.L       PRTLN                  print the line
           BSR.L       CHKIO                  check for listing halt request
           BEO         LS3
           CMP.B       •CTRLS,D0              pause the listing?

