'RETURN<CR>. undoes everything that 'GOSUB' did, and thus
•	
• returns the execution to the command after the most recent
•	
'GOSUB'. If 'STKGOS' is zero, it indicates that we never had
•	
a 'GOSUB' and is thus an error.
•
GOSUB	
BSR.L	
PUSHA
BSR.L	
EXPR
MOVE.L	
A0,-(SP)
MOVE.L DO,D1
BSR.L	
FNDLN
BNE.L	
AHOW
MOVE.L CURRNT,-(SP)
MOVE.L	
STKGOS,-(SP)
CLR.L	
LOPVAR
MOVE.L SP,STKGOS  
BRA	
RUNTSL
save the current 'FOR' parameters  
get line number
save text pointer
find the target line
if not there, say "How?"
found it, save old 'CURRNT'...  
and 'STKGOS'
load new values
RETURN BSR.L	
ENDCHK
MOVE.L STKGOS,D1  
BEQ.L	
()WHAT 
MOVE.L D1,SP
MOVE.L	
(SP)+,STKGOS
MOVE.L	
(SP)+,CURRNT
MOVE.L	
(SP)+,A0
BSR.L	
POPA
BRA	
FINISH 
there should be just a <CR>  
get old stack pointer
if zero, it doesn't exist  
else restore it
and the old 'STKGOS'  
and the old 'CURRNT'
and the old text pointer
and the old 'FOR' parameters  
and we are back home
•	
•• FOR ••• 6 NEXT **•
*	
'FOR' has two forms:
•	
'FOR var-expl TO exp2 STEP expl' and 'FOR var-expl TO exp2'
O	
The second form means the same thing as the first form with a
•	
STEP of positive 1. The interpreter will find the variable 'var'
*	
and set its value to the current value of 'expl'. It also
*	
evaluates 'exp2' and 'expl' and saves all these together with
•	
the text pointer, etc. in the 'FOR' save area, which consisits of
*	
'LOPVAR', 'LOPINC', 'LOPLMT', 'LOPLN', and 'LOPPT'. If there is
*	
already something in the save area (indicated by a non-zero
*	
ILOPVAR'1, then the old save area is saved on the stack before
*	
the new values are stored. The interpreter will then dig in the
*	
stack and find out if this same variable was used in another
*	
currently active 'FOR' loop. If that is the case, then the old
*	
'FOR' loop is deactivated. (i.e. purged from the stack)
*	
'NEXT var' serves as the logical (not necessarily physical) end
*	
of the 'FOR' loop. The control variable 'var' is checked with
•	
the 'LOPVAR'. If they are not the same, the interpreter digs in
*	
the stack to find the right one and purges all those that didn't
*	
match. Either way, it then adds the 'STEP' to that variable and
*	
checks the result with against the limit value. If it is within
*	
the limit, control loops back to the command following the
*	
'FOR'. If it's outside the limit, the save area is purged and
•	
execution continues.
FOR	
BSR.L	
PUSHA
BSR.L	
SETVAL 
MOVE.L A6,LOPVAR
LEA	
TA:35,AI 
save the old 'FOR' save area  
set the control variable  
save its address
use 'EXEC' to test for 'TO'

